# KAVITHA CHANDRAN

kavithachandranmetla@gmail.com |linkedin.com/in/kavithachandran|github.com/KavithaChandran

A calm, steady, and can-do attitude web developer who is Open to new challenges, languages, and frameworks.

## PROFILE SUMMARY

My interest in coding grew from my earlier technical pursuits in electronics and communication engineering – the complex thinking, the logic, and the challenge – are all similar; being intellectually curious, I enjoy creating solutions which open up fresh ideas. My work experience in business management, digital marketing, and entrepreneurship provided me with the opportunity to develop strong people, project, and time management skills; my superpower is the ability to optimize whatever I'm working on. I am a creative, enthusiastic person who dives into new endeavors headfirst and strives to grow through continuous learning and actively volunteer in the community events. In my free time, I love to be occupied with intellectual pursuits, painting, positive minds and books around me.

- Data Analysis and Logical Thinking
- Time & Project Management
- Leading Teams and Motivating Others
- Positivity and Growth Mindset
- Compassion and Empathy
- Mentoring, Guiding, Teaching

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY

## JavaScript | CSS | HTML | MongoDB | FireBase | Web API | React | Node.js | Express | Git | GitHub

#### **Technical Certifications**

Full Stack Web Developer Certification (480+ hours)

Digital Marketing Certification (18 months)

MSSC Production Technician Certification (9 months)

Burlington Code Academy

Apr 2021

Apr 2019

Community College of Vermont

May 2018

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Detail Works VT Williston, VT Mar 2021 – Apr 2021

A subsidiary of Spectrum Youth and Family Services offering full-scale car detailing while giving youths an opportunity to build a resume and obtain the soft skills necessary to keep a job.

#### Web Developer – Capstone Project, Burlington Code Academy

A 4-person Agile-style team tasked with developing a scheduling web application which is automated, interactive, and admin-friendly; the two main focus areas were the appointment scheduler and the admin dashboard.

- Created a database with MongoDB to store scheduled appointments.
- Built an admin portal and dashboard with the ability to modify or cancel appointments, perform broad and filtered searches, and generate reports.
- Created one-tier admin login authentication using Firebase and used Nodemailer and Node-cron to send automated appointment confirmation and reminders to customers
- Led regular client meetings to report on progress and invite feedback on project components
- <u>Technology:</u> CSS, HTML, React, MongoDB, Firebase, Node.js, Nodemailer, Node-cron, GitHub

## Aid the Needy-Non-Profit Organization

## **Founding Member, Board of Trustees**

2012 - present

- Youth-run nonprofit with a mission to identify, empower, and connect students with educational opportunities and provide targeted support for multiple constituencies (e.g. orphans, senior citizens, women, school age children)
- Provide mentorship support to young adults to help with their knowledge and skills to grow.

South Burlington School District

South Burlington, VT

Apr 2017 - Jan 2021

Intervention Teacher Substitute Teacher (full time) Aug 2020 – Jan 2021 (part time) Apr 2017 – July 2020

As an <u>Intervention teacher</u>, provided expertise and intentional support to students who demonstrate behavioral, social and educational challenges. As a <u>Substitute Teacher</u> member, served as a classroom teacher and special educator for grades K-5.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

VT South Indian Burlington, VT Jan 2016 – present

Home-based Indian food takeout and catering business.

#### Owner

Started my own catering business specializing in South Indian food takeout from home.

- Implement business plan and sales strategies while performing daily operations,
- Develop and execute website optimization strategies,
- Distribute weekly Newsletter emails to subscribers using Mailchimp.

#### Sciphics Technology

#### Bangalore, Karnataka, India

(part time) Mar 2019 - present

A government recognised start-up providing support with Digital Marketing, Data Management, and Analytics.

#### **Consultant Partner**

Assist non-profits and small business start-ups with strategic thinking regarding evolving online marketing opportunities to include website optimization, social media strategy, and data management. Examine, track, and analyze social media and website patterns to determine best posting practices.

- Boosted key client's web performance by 25% and gained invaluable consumer insights by researching and analyzing web data and consumer behavior using Google Analytics.
- Increased social media following by 50% for multiple companies by developing and executing online marketing strategies

<u>Latter Rain Ministries</u> Fargo, ND Oct 2018 – Mar 2019

**Digital Marketing Associate** 

Digital Marketing Consultant - Capstone Project, Springboard

Jan 2019 – Mar 2019

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019

Virtually from scratch created, implemented, tracked, analyzed, and optimized Paid Search campaigns. Utilized compelling ad copy, Google AdWords editor, A/B testing, exact phrase vs broad matching, negative keywords, etc. to identify and correct poor performers.

- Originated initial email marketing newsletter and email marketing campaigns with minimal opt-out and high click-through
- This role transformed from a Capstone project to a full time temporary position

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

| Master's in Management                                  | University of Edinburgh, Scotland | Nov 2010 |
|---|-----------------------------------|----------|
| Bachelor's in Electronics and Communication Engineering | Anna University, India            | May 2008 |

## **Health-related Certifications**

Ayurveda Basics Certification (self-paced) Udemy Jun 2020

- Learn how Diet, Weather and activities affect physical and mental health.
- Improve health naturally over chemical products

Aromatherapy Certification (250 hours)

Aromahead Institute

Jan 2020

## OTHER SKILLS

Active Volunteer

Color Run Event Volunteer 2017 – present Rotary Club – India Teaching and Entertainment at Elder Care and Childcare Centers 2006 – 2009

**Professional Skills** 

Applications Google Analytics | Google AdWords Editor
Digital Marketing Link Building Strategy | Social Media Marketing | SEO & PPC Management | MailChimp
Spoken Languages Telugu (native) | Tamil (native) | English (fluent)